H. Corwin Hinshaw Papers 1925-1994 Mss.Ms.Coll.107
American Philosophical Society
H. Corwin Hinshaw Papers, 1925-1994
Mss.Ms.Coll.107
American Philosophical Society
3.75 Linear feet
H. (Horton) Corwin Hinshaw was a physician and pulmonary specialist; the high point of his career was his work with streptomycin, the first anti-microbial drug developed after penicillin. Streptomycin has proven to be effective in combating a variety of bacterial infections, including those that are penicillin-resistant. It was also the first drug used to treat tuberculosis successfully, although the high rate of mutation in the tuberculosis baccilli causes it to build up a resistance to the drug over time. Hinshaw and his collaborator, William H. Feldman, were nominated for the Nobel Prize in Medicine in 1952, but lost out to their colleague, Selman A. Waksman, who first extracted streptomycin in the laboratory. Hinshaw subsequently had a long and distinguished career in medical research, private practice, teaching, and writing. The H. Corwin Hinshaw Papers (1925-1993) contain correspondence, research notes, and manuscripts of published and unpublished works by Hinshaw and his colleagues, as well as published papers by Hinshaw and his colleagues, particularly William H. Feldman. Also included are several videotapes of expert witness testimony and an audiotape of reminiscences. The collection covers much of Hinshaw's career, but is most particularly focused on the development of streptomycin and the treatment of tuberculosis.
Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000
Related Archival Materials note
Selman A. Waksman's papers are held at the American Jewish Archives in Cincinnati, Ohio.
Separated Materials note
Audiovisual materials have been placed in the Audiovisual Division as Rec. 271. Oversized materials from Series II are housed with Oversized materials.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Hinshaw Papers were donated to the APS Library by H. Corwin Hinshaw's daughter, Dorothy Hinshaw Patent, in 2000. The collection was referred to the APS courtesy of the Minnesota Historical Society.
Scope and Contents note
The H. Corwin Hinshaw Papers (1925-1993) contain correspondence, research notes, and manuscripts of published and unpublished works by Hinshaw and his colleagues, as well as published papers by Hinshaw and his colleagues, particularly William Feldman. Also included are several videotapes of expert witness testimony and an audiotape of reminiscences.
One of the strengths of this collection is that it not only gives a good picture of Hinshaw's career and contributions but also a sense of the scientific collaboration taking place both within the Mayo Clinic and between Mayo and other institutions. The research materials in Series II give a strong indication of the teamwork that was necessary to perform the various laboratory experiments and clinical trials that brought streptomycin into the modern medical pharmacopoeia. Particularly engaging is the obvious friendship between Hinshaw and Feldman, which reveals itself throughout much of the collection. There are also some hints at the controversy surrounding the 1952 Nobel Prize in Medicine and the debate about whose streptomycin work actually came first.
The collection covers much of Hinshaw's career, but is most particularly focused on the development of streptomycin and the treatment of tuberculosis. Hinshaw had an acute awareness of the historical significance of this particular aspect of his work, as is evidenced by the materials he chose to preserve and the many explanatory notes he left which interpret and underscore the significance of the materials. In the finding aid, items marked with an asterisk (*) indicate that they are annotated by Hinshaw (or in some cases, Feldman) and that these notes may be of particular interest to researchers.
The papers (7 boxes; 3.75 linear feet) are divided into five series:
Series I. Correspondence, 1943-1993 (1 box; 0.5 linear feet)
Series II. Streptomycin research, 1939-1954 (2 boxes; 1 linear foot)
Series III. Printed materials, 1926-1990 (1.5 boxes; 0.75 linear feet)
Series IV. Miscellaneous materials, 1925-1991 (1 box; 0.5 linear feet)
Series V. Audiovisual materials, 1983-1994 (2 boxes; 0.5 linear feet)
Biographical/Historical note
H. (Horton) Corwin Hinshaw was born August 1, 1902 in Iowa Falls, Iowa, and was raised on an apple farm in the Quaker community of Greenleaf, Idaho. He became a physician and pulmonary specialist instead of a farmer, but ironically the high point of his career was his work with streptomycin, an antibiotic substance extracted from soil. Streptomycin, the first anti-microbial drug developed after penicillin, was a break-through in medical science. It has proven to be effective in combating a variety of bacterial infections, including those that are penicillin-resistant. It was also the first drug used to treat tuberculosis successfully, although the high rate of mutation in the tuberculosis baccilli causes it to build up a resistance to the drug over time. Hinshaw and his collaborator, William H. Feldman, were nominated for the Nobel Prize in Medicine in 1952, but lost out to their colleague, Selman A. Waksman, who first extracted streptomycin in the laboratory. Hinshaw subsequently had a long and distinguished career in medical research, private practice, teaching, and writing.
Hinshaw was the third of six children born to Milas Clark Hinshaw (1873-1955) and Ida Letitia Bushong Hinshaw (1881-1942). He attended Greenleaf Academy in Idaho, and then took his B.S. degree from the College of Idaho in 1923. While at the college, he met Dorothy Youmans (1902-1994) whom he married on August 6, 1924. The Hinshaws had four children; his two sons followed him into medical careers, while one daughter became a zoologist and author, and the other an educator.
After spending a year in advanced studies at the University of Pittsburgh, Hinshaw took an M.S. degree at the University of California, Berkeley in 1926, and completed his Ph.D. at the same institution the following year. From 1927-1931, he taught Parasitology and Bacteriology at the American University in Beirut, Lebanon. Returning to the United States, Hinshaw earned his medical degree at the University of Pennsylvania in 1933. He was subsequently recruited to work at the Mayo Clinic in Rochester, Minnesota, where he developed his interest in diseases of the lung.
The collaboration of Hinshaw and William Feldman dates to 1938, when the two shared a ride home from a tuberculosis conference in St. Paul, Minnesota. After Selman Waksman and Albert Schatz created the first supply of streptomycin in April, 1944, Hinshaw and Feldman decided to try the drug's efficacy in treating "the white plague" of tuberculosis. The first animal trials, conducted at Mayo with tuberculosis-infected guinea pigs, were amazingly successful and encouraged the researchers to expand experimental treatment to human subjects. Although the initial human trials recorded promising success, it subsequently became clear that the tuberculosis baccilli built up a resistance to the drug over time, and the drug was not the hoped for "miracle cure."
In spite of the fact that Hinshaw and his colleagues reported the negative aspects of streptomycin treatment in tuberculosis, the popular press reaction to the initial positive results was so strong that many people still believe that tuberculosis has been "cured." Many medical advances have been made in tuberculosis treatment, but it still kills almost three million people annually. It is a preventable disease that is most effectively treated in its early stages. Streptomycin continues to be used, in combination with other newer drugs, to treat tuberculosis, but there is still an on-going battle as the disease continues to develop drug-resistant strains.
Ironically, William Feldman actually contracted tuberculosis in 1948 as a result of his laboratory work with live tubercle bacilli. According to Hinshaw, this occurrence "threatened [Feldman's] life and ... interrupted the close collaboration which we had enjoyed during the previous ten years." Luckily, a combination drug therapy (including streptomycin and Promin, both of which Feldman helped to develop) enabled Feldman to recover. Hinshaw mused that "It must be a rare circumstance in medical history that a scientist is stricken as a result of his experiments and is also rescued by his own hand."
Following the heady days of early streptomycin research, Hinshaw moved his family to California, where he worked in internal medicine as a pulmonary specialist and served as Clinical Professor of Medicine, Head of the Division of Chest Diseases at Stanford Medical School from 1949-1959. In 1953, he went on a Rutgers-funded "World Tour" to Europe and Asia, where he lectured on treatment of tuberculosis as practiced in the US. In 1955, he was invited to attend the 5th Congreso Argentino de Tisiología, where he presented a paper on current trends in drug therapy for tuberculosis. In 1956, he co-authored the seminal textbook on pulmonary medicine, Diseases of the Chest, with L. Henry Garland, a work that went into four editions. At government invitation, he attended the Sixth All Union Congress on Tuberculosis held in Moscow in 1957 and presented a paper on tuberculosis treatment in the U.S. Hinshaw taught a course on Chest Disease in New Zealand in 1959. In that same year, he became Clinical Professor of Medicine at the University of California Medical School in San Francisco; he held this position actively for the next 20 years, and was named Emeritus Professor in 1979. An interesting early highlight of Hinshaw's career was the work he did with Charles Lindberg on experiments in high-altitude aviation medicine. In his later years, Hinshaw became an expert witness, testifying in numerous legal cases involving respiratory aliments, particularly asbestosis.
Hinshaw authored over 215 articles that appeared in medical and scientific journals. He was professionally active in a number of societies, including the American Thoracic Society, for which he served as president in 1948-1949. In 1990, he received the Mayo Foundation Distinguished Alumnus Award. He died peacefully at home on December 28, 2000 at the age of 98.
Bridge, Ezra; Brown, Henry Allen, 1921-; Cairns, Hugh; Carr, David T.; Chain, Ernst, Sir, 1906-; Doub, Leonard, 1913-; Dubois, R; Déries, G.; Eaton, J. Lloyd; Elias, William F.; Farmer, Chester J.; Feldman, Ruth; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974; Figi, Frederick A.; Graessle, Otto E.; Heilman, Dorothy Henderson, 1905-; Heilman, Fordyce Russell, 1905; Herrell, Wallace Edgar, 1906-; Hinshaw, Dorothy, 1902-1994; Hobson, Lawrence Bennett, 1915-; Hughes, Felix A.; Lehmann, Jörgen; Linz, R.; Major, Randolph Thomas, 1901-; Parsons, Harry G.; Phillips, Samuel, 1908-; Pozzi, Giuseppe; Price, Alison H.; Pyle, Marjorie M.; Rosenow, Edward C. III; Saya, Giovanna; Stearns, William H.; Waksman, Selman A., (Selman Abraham), 1888-1973; Weinshilboum, Richard; Asbestosis; Chemotherapy; Chest Diseases; Human Experimentation in Medicine; Leprosy; Medical Research Personnel; Nobel Prizes; Protozoology; Streptomycin; Tuberculosis
- Series I. Correspondence, 1943-1993; 1 box, 0.5 lin. feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Incoming and outgoing manuscript and typescript letters, carbons, telegrams, and postcards generated throughout Hinshaw's career. Series I is arranged chronologically. The bulk of the correspondence is from Hinshaw's friend and early collaborator, William H. Feldman. The Feldman-Hinshaw correspondence falls into two distinct groupings - third-party letters concerning the early work on streptomycin from 1944, and a group of more personal letters dating from the mid-1960s to about the time of Feldman's death in 1973. There is also some personal correspondence from Feldman's wife, Ruth, from the period before Feldman's last illness and following his death. Additionally, there is correspondence concerning HCH's trip to the V Congreso Argentino de Tisiología in November, 1955 and his work with Dr. Marjorie Pyle on her book for tuberculosis patients (see Series IV for manuscript copy of The Good Fight). Of particular interest are the copy of the 12 July 1946 telegram that Hinshaw sent to his wife, proclaiming, "Undeniable Confirmation that Streptomycin is First Truly Effective Remedy Making This Historically Significant Date" and the 1 October 1991 letter to Dr. Richard Weinshilboum containing reminiscences of the early research and controversies in the development of streptomycin.
  Correspondents in Series I include:
  Carr, David Turner, 1914-
  Chain, Ernst, 1906-1979
  Doub, Leonard, 1913-
  Feldman, Ruth
  Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974
  Hinshaw, Dorothy, 1902-1994
  Hobson, Lawrence Bennett, 1915-
  Lehmann, Jörgen
  Major, Randolph Thomas, 1901-
  Pyle, Marjorie M.
  Rosenow, Edward C. III
  Waksman, Selman Abraham, 1888-1973
  Weinshilboum, Richard
  - Anonymous hate mail, 1 December 1943 (Box 1)
  - 18 September 1944, Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
    Typescript of phone conversation
  - to Waksman, S.A., 19 September 1944; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to Feldman, William H., 28 September 1944; Major, Randolph Thomas, 1901- (Box 1)
  - Waksman, S.A., 9 October 1944; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to Major, Randolph T., 10 October 1944; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 8 November 1944; Waksman, Selman A., (Selman Abraham), 1888-1973 (Box 1)
  - to Hinshaw, Dorothy, 12 June 1946; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
    Telegram - photocopy
  - to HCH, 19 December 1949; Pyle, Marjorie M. (Box 1)
    See Series IV for copy of her manuscript.
  - to HCH, 20 March 1950; Pyle, Marjorie M. (Box 1)
  - to Pyle, Marjorie M., 7 April 1950; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 21 May 1950; Pyle, Marjorie M. (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 21 June 1950; Pyle, Marjorie M. (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 16 March 1953; Chain, Ernst, Sir, 1906- (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 5 May 1955; Waksman, Selman A., (Selman Abraham), 1888-1973 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 6 May 1955; Hobson, Lawrence B. (Box 1)
  - to Waksman, Selman A., 16 May 1955; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
  - to Hobson, Lawrence B., 23 May 1955; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, May 1955; Puga, Carlos G. (Box 1)
    In Spanish; English translation dated 1 August 1955
  - to HCH, 13 June 1955; Izquierdo, Juan A. (Box 1)
  - to Hobson, Lawrence B., 24 June 1955; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
  - to Izquierdo, Juan A., 24 June 1955; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 21 July 1955; Izquierdo, Juan A. (Box 1)
  - to Izquierdo, Juan A., 8 August 1955; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
  - to Puga, Carlos G., 22 August 1955; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 20 September 1955; Hobson, Lawrence B. (Box 1)
  - to Hobson, Lawrence B., 29 September 1955; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 10 October 1955; Waksman, Selman A., (Selman Abraham), 1888-1973 (Box 1)
  - to Waksman, Selman A., 17 October 1955; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 3 November 1955; Riggins, H. McLeod (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 4 August 1956; Lozano (Box 1)
    Telegram
  - to HCH, 8 August 1962; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 11 December 1964; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 12 December 1964; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 24 December 1964; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 29 December 1964; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to Birath, Gosta, 5 January 1965; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 7 January 1965; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to Carr, David T., 16 April 1965; Lehmann, Jörgen (Box 1)
  - to Feldman, William H., 22 April 1965; Carr, David T. (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 27 April 1965; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 17 November 1965; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 30 January 1966; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 7 February 1966; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to Feldman, William H., 23 February 1966; Doub, Leonard, 1913- (Box 1)
    See Feldman to HCH, 23 March 1966
  - to HCH, 21 March 1966; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 23 March 1966; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
    See Doub to Feldman, 23 February 1966
  - to Feldman, William H., 29 March 1966; Lehmann, Jörgen (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 7 April 1966; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 13 April 1966; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 13 August 1966; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 8 November 1966; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 14 December 1966; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to Cawood, Ivan, 7 March 1967; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
  - to Cawood, Ivan, 19 March 1967; Hinshaw, Dorothy, 1902-1994 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 20 April 1967; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to Feldman, William H., 19 May 1967; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
  - to Sharp, Elwood, 19 May 1967; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 27 September 1967; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to Feldman, William H. and Feldman, Ruth, 4 October 1967; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 4 January 1968; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 10 January 1968; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 25 February 1968; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to Carr, David, 29 February 1968; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
  - to Feldman, William H., 29 February 1968; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 10 April 1968; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 14 May 1968; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
    Enclosed E.R. Long's article "Leprosy and Tuberculosis" see Series III
  - to HCH, 29 May 1968; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 15 July 1968; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to Feldman, William H., 5 September 1968; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 8 October 1968; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to Feldman, William H., 17 October 1968; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 26 October 1968; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 29 October 1968; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 4 November 1968; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 21 December 1968; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 30 December 1968; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 1)
  - to HCH (?), 10 August 1968; England, Mrs. B. (Box 1)
  - to Hinshaw, Dorothy, 7 October 1972; Feldman, Ruth (Box 1)
  - to Hinshaw Dorothy and HCH, 21 July [1973]; Feldman, Ruth (Box 1)
  - to Hinshaw, Dorothy and HCH, 1 August 1973; Feldman, Ruth (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 5 October 1973; Taylor, W. Peck (Box 1)
  - to Hinshaw, Dorothy and HCH, 2 November 1973; Feldman, Ruth (Box 1)
  - to Hinshaw, Dorothy and HCH, 17 February 1973; Feldman, Ruth (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 26 July 1984; Anderton, Karen L. (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 4 October 1988; Rosenow, Edward C. III (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 19 February 1990; Knox, Franklin G. (Box 1)
  - to Knox, Franklin G., 26 February 1990; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 26 February 1990; Rosenow, Edward C. III (Box 1)
  - to Weinshilboum, Richard, 1 October 1991; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 1)
  - to HCH, 23 March 1993; Coventry, Mark B. (Box 1)
    Includes 3 p. paper on "Tuberculosis of the Right Wrist"
- Series II. Streptomycin Research, 1939-1945; 2 boxes, 1 lin. foot
  Includes unpublished research reports, patient charts, committee minutes, notes, conference papers and minutes, etc. relating to the development of streptomycin. Series II is arranged chronologically. The bulk of the materials fall between the years of 1944 and 1946, and are the products of research conducted at the Mayo Clinic. This material represents the original research for the development of streptomycin as one of the first modern antibiotic agents. Sixteen clinical reports on streptomycin treatment in human subjects are housed separately with oversize materials.
  Contributors in Series II include:
  Bridge, Ezra
  Brown, Henry Allen, 1921-
  Cairns, Hugh
  Heilman, Dorothy Henderson, 1905-
  Heilman, Fordyce Russell, 1905
  Herrell, Wallace Edgar, 1906-
  Hughes, Felix A.
  Phillips, Samuel, 1908-
  - Excerpt from article, May 1939; Grasset, E. (Box 2)
  - "Streptomycin: Preliminary In Vivo Test Against Mycobacterium Tuberculosis, Var. Hominis", 7 July 1944; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 2)
  - "Streptothricin and Streptomycin", 15 July 1944; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 2)
  - Tuberculosis treated with Streptomycin, October 1944 to June 1947; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 2)
  - Pharmacologic studies on streptomycin, December 1944 to April 1945; Mayo Clinic Research Group in Chemotherapy. (Box 2)
  - Streptomycin Treatment - Patient Records and Research Notes, 1944-1945; Mayo Clinic Research Group in Chemotherapy. (Box 2)
  - Diasone Treatment, 1944, 1946; Mayo Clinic Research Group in Chemotherapy. (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1944, n.d.; Mayo Clinic Research Group in Chemotherapy. (Box 2)
  - Oral Administration of Streptomycin, 14 February 1945; Mayo Clinic Research Group in Chemotherapy. (Box 2)
  - Streptomycin Conference - Chicago, IL, 15 February 1945; Mayo Clinic Research Group in Chemotherapy. (Box 2)
  - Minutes, 14 June 1945; National Research Council (U.S.). Committee on Chemotherapeutics and Other Agents. (Box 2)
  - Streptomycin Conference - Rahway, NJ, 20 June 1945; National Research Council (U.S.). Committee on Chemotherapeutics and Other Agents. (Box 2)
  - Pharmacologic Studies - Discussion, 20 June 1945; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 2)
  - Treatment of tuberculosis - Discussion, 20 June 1945; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 2)
  - "Streptomycin" II, 20 September 1945; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 2)
  - "Report of a trial of Streptomycin in Meningitis due to gram-negative organisms, 1945?; Cairns, Hugh (Box 2)
  - Records, 1945; Colonial Hospital (Box 2)
  - Research notes, 1945; Heilman, Fordyce (Box 2)
  - Streptomycin - Charts, 1945; Heilman, Fordyce (Box 2)
  - "Streptomycin" I, 1945?; Heilman, Fordyce (Box 2)
  - "Standardization of Streptomycin", 1945?; Waksman, Selman A., (Selman Abraham), 1888-1973 (Box 2)
  - "Otological findings...on streptomycin therapy", 14 January 1946; Brown, Henry Allen, 1921- (Box 2)
  - Summary of Patients Treated with Streptomycin, 30 January 1946; Brown, Henry Allen, 1921- (Box 2)
  - Bar Graffs (sic), 7 February 1946; Bridge, Ezra (Box 2)
  - "Clinical Investigation of Streptomycin", 31 May 1946; National Research Council (U.S.). Committee on Chemotherapeutics and Other Agents. (Box 2)
  - Minutes, 13 June 1946; National Research Council (U.S.). Committee on Chemotherapeutics and Other Agents. (Box 2)
  - Report for March 1 - August 31, 1946, 11 September 1946; Streptomycin Committee (Box 2)
  - "Streptomycin", 1 August 1946 1 September 1946; Civilian Production Administration. (Box 2)
  - "Streptomycin Sulfate Squibb", 1946?; Civilian Production Administration. (Box 2)
  - "A Summary of the Present Status of Streptomycin in the Treatment of Tuberculosis", [1947]; Hinshaw, H. Corwin, 1902-2000 (Box 2)
  - "Streptomycin and Resection for Pulmonary Tuberculosis", October 1948; Hughes, Felix A. (Box 2)
  - "Protocols for the Treatment of Tuberculosis by Streptomycin", October 1948; Veterans Administration Hospitals. (Box 2)
  - "Remarks Introducing the Discussion of Paper by Dr. Marc Daniels", July 1951; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 2)
  - "Streptomycin: Historical Aspects of Its Development...", 1954; Feldman, William Hugh, 1892-1974 (Box 2)